The Tigger Movie is a animation, family, comedy
film directed by Jun Falkenstein.
Winnie the Pooh, Piglet, Owl, Kanga, Roo, and Rabbit are preparing a suitable winter home for Eeyore, the
perennially dejected donkey, but Tigger's continual bouncing interrupts their efforts.
Rabbit suggests that Tigger go find others of his kind to bounce with, but Tigger thinks "the most wonderful thing about tiggers
is" he's "the only one!" Just in case though, the joyously jouncy feline sets out to see if he can find relatives.
Tigger / Winnie the Pooh (voice), played by Jim Cummings.
Roo (voice), played by Nikita Hopkins.
Rabbit (voice), played by Ken Sansom.
Piglet (voice), played by John Fiedler.
Eeyore (voice), played by Peter Cullen.
Owl (voice), played by Andre Stojka.
The Tigger Movie is a 2000 American animated musical comedy-drama
film produced by Walt Disney Television Animation.
Written and directed by Jun Falkenstein, it is the second theatrical Winnie the Pooh
feature film, following The Many Adventures of Winnie the Pooh (1977).
It features Pooh's sidekick Tigger searching for his
family tree and other Tiggers like himself.
The film was the first feature-length theatrical Winnie the Pooh film
that was not a collection of previously released shorts.
It is also the first in the original films in which Tigger's is voiced entirely by Jim Cummings (in addition
to Pooh) following the retirement of Tigger's original voice actor Paul Winchell in 1999.
Since 1989, Cummings' had shared the role with Winchell and provided his singing
voice in most projects, with Winchell as the character's speaking voice.
The film features original songs from the Sherman Brothers.
The Tigger Movie was originally planned as a direct-to-video release in 2001, until then–Disney CEO
Michael Eisner heard the songs and decided to release the film in theaters a year early.
It was released in the United States on February 11,
2000, by Buena Vista Pictures Distribution.
The film received generally positive reviews from
critics and grossed $96 million.
The film received three nominations at the Annie Awards, including
Best Direction, Best Voice Acting, and Best Music.
The tone is lighthearted.